<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
	<name>1trickPwnyta's Biotech Patch</name>
	<author>1trickPwnyta</author>
	<packageId>biotechpatch.1trickPwnyta</packageId>
	<modVersion>1.1.0</modVersion>
	<supportedVersions>
		<li>1.5</li>
		<li>1.6</li>
	</supportedVersions>
	<description><![CDATA[This mod makes a handful of small tweaks to the Biotech DLC that are intended to make the game a bit more enjoyable without changing the gameplay too much. Each tweak can be toggled on or off in the mod settings.

<size=18px><color=#5aa9d6>Children</color></size>
  &#8226; The Child Labor: Encouraged precept requires children to be scheduled for at least 4 consecutive hours of work instead of requiring no scheduled recreation, since children don't recreate anyway.
  &#8226; The text for the right-click command "Prioritize growing growth vat" is changed to "Prioritize loading growth vat".
  &#8226; Children will not automatically gain a weird nickname like "Man" or "Dude" or "Bicep" at growth moments.
  &#8226; Children are called by their first names by default, instead of sometimes going by their last names.
  &#8226; Growth moment dialog trait/passion choices are colored. Traits are gray if they would be suppressed by a gene. Passions are red if they would conflict with a gene (such as Awful Mining).
  &#8226; Bug fix: Traits selected at growth moment are unsuppressed by genes that should suppress them (pyrophobia/pyromaniac).
  &#8226; Lactators can stop breastfeeding before the baby is full if something more important comes up (such as their own needs not being met).
  &#8226; Pawns won't move babies to a safer temperature until the baby has at least initial heatstroke/hypothermia.

<size=18px><color=#5aa9d6>Genetics</color></size>
  &#8226; The auto-wake setting is enabled by default for deathresters.
  &#8226; A message appears at the top of the screen when a deathrester wakes up.
  &#8226; Pawns with the webbed phalanges gene don't care about being soaking wet.
  &#8226; The Health tab can be used to order xenogerm implantation even for xenogerms that are forbidden to the patient.
  &#8226; An alert appears on the right side of the screen when a pawn is deficient in a drug they need in order to survive because of their genes.
  &#8226; When ordering a pawn to priotitize creating a xenogerm, they will do it until finished instead of getting bored and leaving after a few seconds.
  &#8226; Kill thirst is satisfied by killing in melee combat, regardless of weapon type equipped.
  &#8226; Bug fix: Same xenogene/endogene can both cancel each other out if they give the same trait.
  &#8226; Bug fix: Children of a custom xenotype and another custom xenotype or baseliner are labeled as baseliner.

<size=18px><color=#5aa9d6>Mechanoids</color></size>
  &#8226; Colony mechanoids are shown in the colonist bar. Instead of mood, charge level is shown.
  &#8226; Mechs can be ordered to move outside the mechanitor's command range, since zones could be used to accomplish this anyway.
  &#8226; Friendly mechs are assigned auto-repair be default.
  &#8226; Friendly mechs can be controlled even when their mechanitor is on a caravan, since the mechanitor doesn't have to be on the same map anyway.
  &#8226; Friendly mechs can self-charge on top of power conduits and other non-chair standable buildings.
  &#8226; Friendly mechs remember their control group assignment upon being resurrected.
  &#8226; Friendly mechs with no energy who need to be carried to a recharger use a different symbol (power outage symbol vs. self charge symbol) and get an alert on the right side of the screen.
  &#8226; Friendly mechs can be given right-click orders to prioritize specific tasks, both while undrafted and drafted, similar to humans.

<size=18px><color=#5aa9d6>Miscellaneous</color></size>
  &#8226; Allow hemogen farming any colonist, not just prisoners. This adds a checkbox to the health tab.
  &#8226; No more message spam when extracting hemogen from a prisoner of a hostile faction.
  &#8226; No more message spam when wastepacks deteriorate outside of the home area.

________________________________________________

<size=18px><color=#5aa9d6>Updates</color></size>
01/18/2026: Add ability to hemogen farm any colonist, add kill thirst satisfaction for any melee combat, show mech charge level in colonist bar instead of mood, remove fixes/features that have since been added in vanilla, bug fixes with pawn names and mechanitor mechs.
10/07/2025: Fix errors when pawn nicknames are handled outside gameplay
09/10/2025: Fix children first name feature
06/16/2025: Update to 1.6, remove features now vanilla
05/21/2025: Fix conflict with Pawn Name Variety, fix pawn name errors when reloading saves
04/13/2025: Fix conflict with Character Editor

<size=18px><color=#5aa9d6>Credits</color></size>
  &#8226; Mod icon: twitter.com/mouse_draws
  &#8226; Positive thoughts: Viewers like you
	]]></description>
	<url>https://github.com/1trickPwnyta/BiotechPatch</url>
	<modDependencies>
		<li>
			<packageId>brrainz.harmony</packageId>
			<displayName>Harmony</displayName>
			<steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/2009463077</steamWorkshopUrl>
			<downloadUrl>https://github.com/pardeike/HarmonyRimWorld/releases/latest</downloadUrl>
		</li>
	</modDependencies>
</ModMetaData>
